President's Office Records, 1927-1981
University of Houston Libraries
- Subject Files (Box 1-50)
  - Student Association, 1972-1973 (Box 44, Folder 1-3)
  - Student Association, 1973 (Box 44, Folder 4-5)
  - Student Association, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 6-8)
  - Student Association, 1974-1977 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Student Association, 1974-1975 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Student Conduct Cases, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Student - Correspondence re:, 1956-1970 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Student - Deceased, 1955-1969 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Student Identity Cards, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Student - Leadership Conference, 1961-1966 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Student Life Division, 1972-1974 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Student Life Human Relations Committee, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Student Loan Policy, 1964-1968 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Student Loan and Scholarship Corporation, 1939-1957 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Student Organizations, 1955-1963 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Student Organizations, 1969-1973 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Student Organizations (Box 44, Folder 22-34)
    - AABL, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 22-24)
    - AABL, Correspondence re:, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 25-27)
    - AABL, Correspondence re:, 1969-1970 (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - AABL, News Releases, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - LOMAS, 1969-1970 (Box 44, Folder 30)
    - MAYO, 1970-1973 (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - SDS, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 32)
    - SDS, 1969-1972 (Box 44, Folder 33)
    - SDS, Bernhardt-Haile Case, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 34)
  - Student Power, 1966-1968 (Box 44, Folder 35)
  - Student Power [Clippings], 1966-1968 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Student Protests - Trees at Fine Arts Center Site, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Student - Recruitment of Superior, 1968-1969 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Student Services Conference, 1963-1966 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Student Services Fees, Allocations of, 1971-1972 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Student Services Office, 1966-1974 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Student Traffic Court, 1968-1970 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Student Traffic Court, 1971-1972 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Student Unrest, 1968-1969 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Student Unrest, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Student Unrest, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Student Unrest, 1969-1970 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Student Unrest, 1970-1972 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Swimming Pool, 1953-1963 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Taub Family, 1955-1956 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Teacher Retirement, 1939-1974 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Teaching Excellence Awards, 1972-1974 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Teaching Excellence Awards, 1975-1977 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Technology Advisory Committee, 1956-1960 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Technology, College of, 1971-1972 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Technology, College of, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Technology, College of, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Technology, College of, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Technology, College of, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Technology, College of, 1976-1978 (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - Technology, Four-year Program, 1964-1965 (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - Technology, Four-year Program, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Technology, Four-year Program, 1967-1968 (Box 45, Folder 28)
  - Television Advisory Committee, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 29)
  - Television, Dedication of KUHT, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 30)
  - Television, Educational, 1960-1964 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Television, Educational, 1962-1963 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Television, Educational, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Tenure Policies, 1953, 1950-1955 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Texas A&M, 1972-1974 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Texas Association of College Teachers, 1970-1974 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Texas Education Agency, 1973-1974 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Texas Education Agency, 1974-1978 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Texas Southern University, 1968-1970 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Texas Southern University, 1971-1973 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Texas Southern University, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Texas Systems of Natural Laboratories, Inc., 1970-1973 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Texas Technological University, 1970-1974 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Tex-Pirg, 1972 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Tex-Pirg, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Tex-PIRG, 1973-1977 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Tiller, Frank M., 1963 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Traffic and Parking Regulations, 1969-1970 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Travel Regulations Under State, 1971-1977 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Treece, Jerry, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Tuition and Fees, 1970-1972 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - United Fund, 1964-1972 (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - University Center, 1970-1974 (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - University Center Dedication, 1966-1967 (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - University Center Policy Board, 1966-1974 (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - University Center Program Council, 1966-1973 (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - University Festival, 1964-1967 (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - University Oaks Restrictions, 1947-1962 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - University of Houston System, 1975-1976 (Box 47, Folder 2-3)
  - University of Houston Women's Association, 1962-1974 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - University of Texas, 1971-1974 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - University of Thought, 1970-1973 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - University Relations, Office of, 1961-1973 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Urban Affairs, 1968-1973 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Vacations and Absences, 1951-1969 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Vending Machine, 1949-1953 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Vice President (Box 47-48)
    - Dean of Students, 1970 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Dean of Students, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Dean of Students, 1972-1973 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Dean of Students, 1973-1974 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Dean of Students William Harry Sharp, 1974-1975 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Dean of Students William Harry Sharp, 1976 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Executive and Dean of Facilities, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Executive and Dean of Facilities, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Executive and Dean of Faculties, 1974-1975 (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Executive and Dean of Faculties, 1976 (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Facilities Planning and Construction, 1972-1973 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Facilities Planning and Construction, 1974-1975 (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Facilities Planning and Operations, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Facilities Planning and Operations, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - Facilities Planning and Operations, 1973-1974 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Facilities Planning and Operations, 1974-1975 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Facilities Planning and Operations, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Public Affairs, 1973-1974 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Public Affairs, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Public Affairs, Allen Commander, 1974-1976 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Public Affairs, Allen Commander, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Senior and Treasurer, 1956-1968 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Senior and Treasurer, 1969-1978 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Student Life, 1968-1972 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - University Development, 1968-1970 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - University Development, 1971-1973 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - University Development, 1973-1974 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - University Development, 1974-1975 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - University Development, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - University Development Nicholson Consultants, 1975-1976 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - UH Victoria (Box 48-49)
    - Victoria, 1972-1973 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Victoria, 1973-1976 (Box 48, Folder 18-19)
    - Victoria Campus, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 20-22)
    - Victoria Campus, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Victoria Campus, 1976 (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
    - Victoria Campus, 1977 (Box 49, Folder 3-5)
    - Victoria Campus, 1976-1977 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Victoria Campus, undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Affirmative Action Program, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Degree Program, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Maxson, Dr. Robert C., Chancellor, 1978-1979 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Southern Association, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Vacation and Absences, 1978-1979 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Visiting Committee, Report of the, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - VISTA, 1963-1970 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Wealthy Residents, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Weingarten, Abe House Donated to UH 3612 Parkwood, 1959-1963 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Welch, Robert A. Chair, 1962-1974 (Box 49, Folder 18-19)
  - Werlin, Joseph S. - Memorial Scholarship, 1967-1968 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, 1963-1972 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Who's Who in America, 1962-1974 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Will - Lucas Case, 1951-1952 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Will - McGuire Case, 1950-1952 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - William, Clanton Ware - Ex-President, 1952-1976 (Box 49, Folder 25-27)
  - Wills and Bequeaths, 1957-1969 (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Woodlands, The, 1974-1975 (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Woodlands, The, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Woodlands, The, 1975-1976 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Wortham Theater Dedication, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Xerox, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Yarborough, Ralph - Former U. S. Senator, 1958-1972 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Yardley, William A., 1970-1971 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - YMCA and YWCA, 1960-1979 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Zwicker, Col. M. H. - Dr. of Laws, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 8)
- Mission Self-Study (Box 50-51)
  This series contains twenty-seven folders that relate to the University's Mission Self-Study. President Hoffman and Vice President Emmett Fields announced the Mission Self-Study at the General Faculty Meeting on January 11, 1974. The purpose of the study was to fulfill a requirement by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools that each member institution conduct a self-study at least once each decade for re-accreditation purposes. The materials date from 1974 to 1976 and include extensive data used in the study and the results from the study itself. The original folder order was chronological and has been maintained except where folders were obviously misfiled.
  - U.H. Mission Self-Study Program Inventory Instructional Programs, December 1974 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - U.H. Mission Self-Study Program Inventory For Colleges III Public Service Programs, 1974 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - University of Houston Central Campus Mission Self-Study Report, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence relating to the Self Study, 1975-1976 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence relating to the Self Study, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974-1975 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Letters Against Cancellation of the Home Economics Program, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 16-19)
  - Faculty Senate Recommendations on Mission: Self-Study, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous Materials Relating to the Self-Study: Steering Committee Agenda Student Petitions against Self-Study Recommendations, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - UH Mission Self-Study Steering Committee Minutes' Digest, 1974-1976 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Final Report of the Steering Committee for the Mission Self-Study University of Houston, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 5-6)
  - University of Houston Central Campus Mission Self-Study Report Appendix H, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - President Philip G. Hoffman's Comments to Board of Regents, March 4, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Mission Self-Study Report of the Visiting Committee (Reaffirmation Committee) of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 9-10)
  - Mission Self-Study Speech, undated (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - University of Houston Self-Study Steering Committee-Philip G. Hoffman, 1972-1973 (Box 51, Folder 12-15)
  - Analysis of Mission Self-Study Task Force 8 Final Report University of Houston System, September 10, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 16)
- Coordinating Board (Box 51-55)
  This series contains eighty-five folders that relate to the Higher Education Coordinating Board. The Higher Education Coordinating Act of 1965 provided that the Coordinating Board shall "review periodically all degree and certificate programs offered by institutions of higher education…." (Section 10, Paragraph [5]). The materials in this series are extensive in nature consisting primarily of meeting minutes and date from 1968-1976. The series is divided into two sub-series, Active and Inactive, based on the order received.
  - Active (Box 51-53)
    - Meeting, September 16, 1968 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Meeting, January 21, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Meeting, February 25, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Meeting, April 21, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Meeting, June 9, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Meeting, July 21, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Special Meeting, July 28, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Meeting, September 30, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Meeting, October 20, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Meeting, November 20, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Meeting, December 1, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Meeting, January 19, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Meeting, January 20, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Meeting, March 2, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Meeting, April 13, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Meeting, June 8, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Meeting, July 19, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Meeting, September 28, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Meeting, October 31, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Meeting, January 18, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Meeting, March 8, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Meeting, April 19, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Meeting, July 16, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Meeting, October 18, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Meeting, December 6, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Meeting, January 17, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Meeting, February 14, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Meeting, April 18, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Meeting, May 14, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Meeting, July 18, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Special Meeting, September 12, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Special Meeting, October 17, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - Special Meeting, Austin, Texas, December 11, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Special Meeting, Austin, Texas, January 15, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Special Meeting, Austin, February 25, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Special Meeting, Thompson Center, April 23, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - Special Meeting, Austin, Texas, July 16, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - Special Meeting, December 3, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - Index of Minutes, 1973-1976 (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - Academic Programs, 1970-1972 (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - Academic Programs, 1972-1976 (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - Directions for New Programs, 1967-1973 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Directions for New Programs, 1973-1975 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Directions for New Programs, 1975-1976 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Directions for New Programs, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - General, January 1975-Aug. 1975 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - General, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - General, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 7-10)
  - Inactive 1969-1976 (Box 53-55)
    - Role and Scope, 1968-1976 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - 1971-73 Biennium, 1971-1973 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Coordinating Board, January 19, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Extension of January 19, 1970 meeting, February 6, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Special Meeting, UH Campus, March 13, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Coordinating Board, April 20, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Coordinating Board, July 20, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Coordinating Board, September 9, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Coordinating Board, October 19, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Coordinating Board, December 4, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Coordinating Board, January 18, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Coordinating Board, February 25, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Coordinating Board, April 23, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Coordinating Board, May 15, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Coordinating Board, July 19, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Coordinating Board, August 27, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Coordinating Board, October 15, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Coordinating Board, November 19, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Legislative Appropriations, 1969-1970 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Legislative Appropriations, 1970-1971 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Student Loan Activities, 1970-1971 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Student Loan Activities, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Student Loan Activities, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - Student Loan Activities, 1973-1974 (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - Student Loan Program, 1974-1976 (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - Student Loan Program, 1970-1971 (Box 54, Folder 20)
    - General, 1970-1971 (Box 54, Folder 21)
    - General, 1972-1973 (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
    - General, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 4-5)
    - Dr. Bevington Reed Commissioner of Higher Education, 1968-1969 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Dr. Bevington Reed Commissioner of Higher Education, 1969-1971 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Dr. Bevington Reed Commissioner of Higher Education, 1972-1975 (Box 55, Folder 8)
- President's Cabinet (Box 55-56)
  This series contains twenty-five folders that relate to meetings of the President's Cabinet. These materials are extensive in nature and include agendas and minutes for most of the President's Cabinet meetings from September 1977 through October 1979. The Cabinet met generally on a monthly basis to discuss significant issues facing the University. These issues included, but were not limited to, the financial affairs of the university, search processes for senior level management positions, building expansions, and major renovations.
  - Meeting, September 9, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Meeting, September 28, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Meeting, November 18, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Meeting, December 16, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Meeting, January 23, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Meeting, February 24, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Meeting, April 21, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Meeting, May 18, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 16)
  - Meeting, June 16, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 17)
  - Meeting, July 26, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 18)
  - Meeting, September 15, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 19)
  - Meeting, October 16, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 20)
  - Meeting, November 27, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 21)
  - Meeting, January 15, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 22)
  - Meeting, January 29, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 23)
  - Meeting, February 12, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 24)
  - Meeting, March 26, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 25)
  - Meeting, April 16, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Meeting, April 30, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Meeting, May 11, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Meeting, June 4, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Meeting, June 18, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Meeting, July 16, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Meeting, September 14, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Meeting, October 12, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 8)
- Investment Investigation (Box 56-59)
  This series containing 126 folders covers almost every aspect of the largest scandal in the history of the University of Houston, which involved short-term investments made on behalf of the university resulting in the loss of several millions of dollars. The materials date from 1970 to 1981, with the majority dating between the years of 1976 and 1978. The files in this series are presumed to be the President's office files and they consist of a variety of materials including reports, correspondence, financial documents, affidavits, and news clippings. This series has been divided into two sub-series based on how it arrived at the Archives. The two sub-series are General and Vice President Singleton's In-house Investigation. The materials within the sub-series were in no order so the Archivist has imposed one. All oversized materials have been boxed separately and are found at the end of this series.
  - General (Box 56, Folder 9-30)
    The items in this sub-series date from 1975-1981 and the folders have been arranged in roughly chronological order.
    - Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Community Service, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Final Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on University Finances, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Investment Investigation, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Cullen Center Bank and Trust, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Samuel A. Harwell, 1977-1978 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Bank of the Southwest, 1977-1978 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - First City National Bank, 1977-1978 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Investment Investigation, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Texas Commerce Bank, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Patrick D. Sullivan against the University of Houston, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Short Term Investments, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Testimony Before House of Representatives By Philip Hoffman, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 20)
    - Dr. Champagne-Student Profile Analysis, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Dr. Champagne-V.P. Academic Program Development and Coordination, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 22)
    - National Association of State Universities and Land-grant Colleges, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 23)
    - Investment Investigation-Arthur Young and Company, 1977-1979 (Box 56, Folder 24)
    - Investment Investigation-Japan California Bank Against the University of Houston, 1977-1979 (Box 56, Folder 25)
    - Investment Investigation-Erlich-Bober and Co. Against the University of Houston, 1978-1979 (Box 56, Folder 26)
    - Investment Investigation-University of Houston against Bevill, Bresler, and Schulman, Inc., 1978-1979 (Box 56, Folder 27)
    - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 28)
    - Dr. Champagne-V.P. Academic Program Development and Coordination, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 29)
    - Dr. Champagne-V.P. Academic Program Development and Coordination, 1980-1981 (Box 56, Folder 30)
  - Vice President Singleton's In-house Investigation (Box 56-59)
    President Hoffman and the Board of Regents charged Vice President Roger Singleton to analyze the activities that had led to the Board of Regent's investigation into the university's investment fund activity. This sub-series consists primarily of working files and correspondence that he used during his investigation. The materials in this series include correspondence amongst the parties involved, copies of ledger entries and financial transactions, and other relevant materials. This sub-series has been divided into five sub-sub-series: Roger Singleton; Douglas G. MacLean; Correspondence; Financial, Banking, and Legal Materials; and General Research and Reference Materials.
    - Roger Singleton (Box 56-57)
      The university hired Roger Singleton in 1969 as assistant dean and assistant professor of accounting in the College of Business Administration. Later he served as Vice President and Dean of Faculties on an interim basis and as Executive Vice President of the University of Houston System. This sub-sub-series relates directly to Singleton himself and is arranged chronologically.
      - Short-term Investment Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 56, Folder 31)
      - Short-term Investment, 1976-1979 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Short-term Investment Correspondence, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Short-term Investment Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Dr. Singleton, March 31, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - Items for Foundation Executive Committee, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - Recap of Events Pertaining to Short-term Investment Investigation, 1977-1978 (Box 57, Folder 6)
      - Affidavit, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 7)
      - Meeting of UHAPWA, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 8)
      - Re-letter Rating Agencies - Bond Issues, 1973-1978 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Douglas G. MacLean, Vice President (Box 57, Folder 10-20)